iata.org 2011-06-05

# Privacy Policy

(Effective April 05, 2007) 

IATA respects your privacy and is committed to protecting it. IATA provides this Privacy Policy to inform you of our privacy practices and of the choices you can make about the way your information is collected online and how that information is used. IATA recognizes the need to protect the personally identifiable information you share with us, which mainly consists of any information by which you can be identified, such as name, address and telephone number. 

By registering on this site, by submitting any information through the use of this site, or by otherwise accessing or using this site, you agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy and consent to the policies and practices described for the collection, use or disclosure of personal information. 

### 1\. Sites covered by this Privacy Policy

This Privacy Policy applies to all IATA owned websites and domains, and our wholly owned subsidiaries ("IATA websites.") 

### 2\. Types of information we collect

This Privacy Statement covers personal information and non-personal data collection and aggregate reporting. 

> **a)“Personal information”** is information that is associated with your name or personal identity. IATA uses personal information to understand better your needs and interests and to provide you with better service. Once you choose to provide us with personal information, you can be assured it will be used only to support your customer relationship with IATA. We take seriously the trust you place in us. IATA will not sell, rent or lease your personal information to others. 
> 
> On some IATA websites, you can order products or services, participate in surveys, request information, subscribe to marketing or support materials, register yourself or your IATA products, or apply for a job or internship at IATA or otherwise be required to provide personal information for other purposes. The types of personal information you provide to us on these pages may include name, address, phone number, e-mail address, user IDs and passwords, billing and transaction information, credit card information, contact preferences, educational and employment background, and job interest data. To personalize our websites, services or communications and improve our products and services, we may also ask you to provide us with information regarding your personal or professional interests, demographics, and experiences with our products or services. Providing this additional information is optional. 
> 
> **b)“Non-personal information”** is data about usage and service operation that is not associated with a specific personal identity. IATA may collect and analyse non-personal information visitors’ domains to evaluate how visitors use the IATA websites or otherwise analyze this data for trends and statistics purposes. Non-personal data we collect may include the pages visited on the IATA websites, unique URLs visited within IATA websites, browser type and IP address, but the individual visitor’s personal information remains anonymous. 
> 
> Most non-personal data is collected via cookies or other analysis technologies. On most IATA websites, we use cookies, web beacons and other technologies for data analysis and personalization services so that we can better serve you with customized information when you return to our site. We also use cookies and web beacons to help us measure the effectiveness of our web communication and marketing in order to improve our site, products, offers and marketing strategy. 
> 
> IATA also places ads on other websites that may use cookies. 
> 
> Cookies are identifiers which a website can send to your browser to keep on your computer to facilitate your next visit to the IATA websites. To learn more, read IATA use of cookies, web beacons and third party ads. You can set your browser to notify you when you are sent a cookie, giving you the option to decide whether or not to accept it. If you do not wish to allow your session visitation information to be aggregated and analyzed by our web analytics service, you can opt-out in accordance with the procedure set forth in Section 9, “Your privacy preferences and opting out”. 

### 3\. Collected information

We've structured the IATA websites so that, in general, you can visit IATA on the web without identifying yourself or revealing any personal information. We make this notice readily available on our home page and at the bottom of every IATA web page. 

There are times when we may collect personal information from you. It is our intent to inform you before we do that and to tell you what we intend to do with the information. Generally, you will have the option not to provide the information, and in the future you will be able to "opt out" of certain uses of the information in accordance with the procedure set forth in Section 9, “Your privacy preferences and opting out”. If you choose not to provide the information we request, you can still visit most of the IATA websites, but you may be unable to access certain options, offers and services. 

### 4\. Links to non-IATA websites

The IATA websites may provide links to third-party companies websites for your convenience and information. If you access those links, you will leave the IATA website. IATA does not control those sites, their content or their privacy practices, which may differ from IATA's. We do not endorse or make any representations about third-party websites. The personal information you choose to give to unrelated third parties is not covered by this IATA Privacy Policy. We encourage you to review the privacy policy of any company before submitting your personal information. Some third-party companies may choose to share their personal data with IATA; that sharing is governed by that third-party company's privacy policy. 

### 5\. Children's privacy

IATA is committed to protecting the privacy needs of children and we encourage parents and guardians to take an active role in their children's online activities and interests. IATA does not knowingly collect information from children under the age of 13 and IATA does not target its websites to children under 13. 

### 6\. How we use your information

IATA uses your personal information to provide you with services and to help us better understand your needs and interests. Specifically, we use your information to help you complete a transaction or order, to communicate with you, to provide service and support, to update you on products, services and benefits, to personalise promotional offers, to personalize some IATA websites, or for other related purposes. Occasionally we may also use your information to contact you for market research regarding IATA products or services. 

We will give you the opportunity to choose your privacy preferences regarding such communications (see Section 9, "Your privacy preferences and opting out"). Credit card information is used only for payment processing and fraud prevention. Sensitive personal information is collected only to facilitate our financial service providers' credit decisions and will be shared with them only with your permission. Credit card information and sensitive personal data are not used for any other purpose by our financial services providers or IATA and will not be kept longer than necessary for providing the services.  
In order to offer you a more consistent and personalized experience in your interactions with IATA, information collected through one IATA service may be combined with information obtained through other IATA services in accordance with your specifications. 

IATA is a global organization, with legal entities, business processes, management structures, and technical systems that cross borders. Our privacy practices are designed to provide protection for your personal information, all over the world. We may share your personal information within IATA and transfer it to countries in the world where we do business. Some countries may provide less legal protection for your information. In such countries IATA will still handle information in the manner we describe here. 

Although we use all reasonable means to ensure that the information you provide to us is not used by third parties for purposes other than those described in this Privacy Policy, IATA is not responsible for any improper use of your personal information that is beyond our reasonable control. 

Non-personal data is aggregated for reporting about IATA websites usability, performance and effectiveness. It is used to improve the customer experience, usability and site content. 

**7\. Who we share your information with**

IATA will not sell, rent or lease your personal information to others. IATA will not share your personal information with third parties except in responding to your requests for products or services. Your permission will be requested when you submit your information. IATA shares customer information across IATA-owned business entities and companies working on our behalf, but only as described in Section 6 "How we use your information". 

IATA contracts with third-party service providers and suppliers to deliver complete products, services and customer solutions and benefits as described in Section 6 "How we use your information". Suppliers and service providers are required to keep confidential the information received on behalf of IATA consistent with this Privacy Policy and may not use it for any purpose other than to carry out the services they are performing for IATA. These service providers may change or we may contract with additional service providers to better accommodate our customers. 

IATA will not share personal information with any other third parties without your permission, unless to: (i) respond to duly authorized information requests of governmental authorities; (ii) comply with any law, regulation, subpoena, or court order, (iii) help prevent fraud or to enforce or protect the rights and properties of IATA or its subsidiaries; or (iv) to protect the personal safety of IATA employees and third parties on IATA property. 

Circumstances may arise where, whether for strategic or other business reasons, IATA decides to sell, buy, merge or otherwise reorganize businesses in some countries. Such a transaction may involve the disclosure of personal information to prospective or actual purchasers, or receiving it from sellers. It is IATA’s practice to seek appropriate protection for information in these types of transactions. 

**8\. Your choices**

IATA gives you the choice of receiving a variety of information that complements our products and services. You can subscribe to receive certain product and service specific information and IATA-wide marketing communications. IATA-wide communications may include new product information, special offers, or an invitation to participate in market research, etc. We give you a choice regarding delivery of IATA-wide communications by postal mail, fax, e-mail and telephone. 

You can make or change your choices at the data collection point or through IATA’s online customer registration tools. Please refer to Section 9 for further instructions. We will make every effort to honor your preferences. This option does not apply to communications for the purpose of administering order completion, contracts, support, product safety warnings or driver updates. 

### 9\. Your privacy preferences and opting out

**Non-subscription services  
** IATA will not use your personal information for a different purpose than the one stated when you provided your data. Examples of unrelated uses include sending communications about special offers, product information, and marketing messages. You can, however, choose to receive these types of non-subscription communications by following the instructions below. 

> **Online** : You can make your choice regarding these communications by using the IATA customer registration tools, as applicable, to set your privacy preferences (available in the English language only). 

    * If you have never registered with the IATA customer registration tools, create your privacy preferences; 
    * If you have registered with the IATA customer registration tool in the past, you may edit your privacy preferences on the IATA customer registration tool (requires a user ID and password). 

> **Offline:** Please specify your privacy preferences by writing to IATA at [imc@iata.org](mailto:imc@iata.org). Be sure to provide your name, e-mail and postal address in all correspondence. 

**Subscription services**  
To opt-out of receiving communications you have expressly requested (such as e-mail newsletters, updates, etc.), use any of the following methods: 

  * Select the e-mail "opt-out" or "unsubscribe" link, or follow the opt-out instructions included in each subscription communication; 
  * Return to the web page(s) where you originally registered your preferences and follow the opt-out instructions; 
  * Write to IATA - be sure to provide your name, e-mail and postal address, and relevant information about your IATA subscriptions and registrations: 
    * IATA e-Marketing services, MACS  
800 Place Victoria  
PO Box 113  
Montreal - H4Z 1M1  
Quebec - Canada  
Fax: +1 514 874 9632   
E-mail: [imc@iata.org](mailto:imc@iata.org)

### 10\. Your information and third-party companies

Certain IATA services may be linked with those from third-party companies, some which offer you the option to share with both IATA and the third party personal data you provide. Examples include to request communications from IATA marketing or solution partners, or to enable order completion through a reseller. We will not share your personal information with those third-party companies unless you make that choice. 

IATA may share information with third parties acting on behalf of IATA and who may be located in other geographies. These third parties are under contract to IATA and bound by terms of confidentiality and the same data privacy rules in usage at IATA. 

### 11\. Access to and accuracy of your information

IATA strives to keep your personal information accurate. We have implemented technology, management processes and policies to maintain customer data accuracy. We will provide you with access to your information, including making reasonable effort to provide you with online access and the opportunity to change your information. To protect your privacy and security, we will also take reasonable steps to verify your identity, such as a password and user ID, before granting access to your data. Certain areas of IATA’s websites may limit access to specific individuals through the use of passwords and other personal identifiers.   
The most effective way to view and change your personal information is to return to the web page where you originally submitted your data and follow the instructions on that web page or use the IATA customer registration tools. 

### 12\. Keeping your information secure

IATA is committed to protecting the information you provide us. To prevent unauthorized access or disclosure, to maintain data accuracy, and to ensure the appropriate use of the information, IATA has in place appropriate physical and managerial procedures to safeguard the information we collect. 

We use Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) encryption when collecting or transferring sensitive data such as credit card information. SSL encryption is designed to make the information unreadable by anyone but us. This security measure is working when you see either the symbol of an unbroken key or closed lock (depending on your browser) on the bottom of your browser window. 

If any user of this website suspects IATA has handled its personal information in a manner that does not comply with this Privacy Policy, please contact us. 

### 11\. Changes to this Statement

If there are updates to the terms of IATA’s online Privacy Policy, we will post those changes and update the revision date in this document, so you will always know what information we collect online, how we use it, and what choices you have. For material changes to this Privacy Policy, IATA will provide notification to affected customers. 

### 13\. Contacting us

We value your opinions. If you have comments or questions about our Privacy Policy, please email us at [privacy@iata.org](mailto:privacy@iata.org) or write to us at the following address: 

  * IATA Legal Services  
800 Place Victoria  
PO Box 113  
Montreal - H4Z 1M1  
Quebec - Canada  
Fax: +1 514-874-1789
